learningally.org 2019-12-13

# Audio Books for Dyslexia & Learning Disabilities | Learning Ally

Updated: November 1, 2019

Learning Ally (referred to below “ **we** ” or “ **us** ”)’s mission is to promote personal achievement when access and reading are barriers to learning by advancing the use of accessible and effective educational solutions. Our website, smartphone app and other services (collectively, the “ **Services** ”) are important tools in the pursuit of this mission. 

We are committed to safeguarding and protecting the personally identifiable information (“ **Personally Identifiable Information** ”) that we gather from individuals like you (a “ **User** ” or “ **Users** ”) who utilize our Services or contact us. 

Our Privacy Policy below explains how we collect, store and use User information gathered through our Services. Users can update their contact or billing information, email subscription or direct mail preferences, by emailing [custserv@LearningAlly.org](mailto:custserv@learningally.org). 

Users who provide us with information on behalf of other Users (e.g., parents, guardians) should be aware that this Policy also applies to the collection, storage and use of those other Users’ Personally Identifiable Information. Users in this situation should ensure that they have such powers, duties and consents as reasonably required from those other Users before contacting us on their behalf or using our Services on their behalf. 

We comply with applicable laws that impose additional responsibilities on Learning Ally beyond those stated in this Policy in connection with the treatment of Personally Identifiable Information. 

## Collecting Personally Identifiable Information

We do not collect Personally Identifiable Information from a User unless they provide it to us voluntarily and knowingly. Users can do so by registering for our Services, requesting information from us, submitting a volunteer request or by making a donation, whether by website, smartphone app, phone or otherwise. By doing any of the foregoing, Users are acknowledging that they are providing us with their Personally Identifiable Information **voluntarily** and **in accordance with this Policy.**

We do not sell names or other personal data that we collect through our Services, nor do we store any credit card information. 

#### (a) Contact and Other Account Information:

We collect Personally Identifiable Information directly from a User when they create an online account with us for our Services, or otherwise contact us with an information or volunteer request. This type of information may include: 

  * name;
  * email address;
  * date of birth;
  * telephone number;
  * company or group of affiliation; and
  * the reason for contact with us.

We collect this information in order to manage that User’s relationship with us, including in order to facilitate the use of our Services, facilitate the payment of donations, and facilitate communication with us. 

We collect dates of birth, specifically, in order to make age-appropriate recommendations to Users when they use our Services, and otherwise to increase the functionality and relevance of our Services. 

#### (b) Disability Verification Information

We collect Personally Identifiable Information related to a User’s disability, as applicable, when they choose to use our Services and provide us with a Certificate of Eligibility (found here) or other proof of disability. This information is limited to one of the conditions qualifying for our Services under Marrakesh Treaty-implementing legislation in the jurisdiction of residence, such as: 

  * the status of the disability, whether a specific learning, reading accommodation, visual disability and/or physical disability; and
  * similar, related information as requested from time to time.

(collectively, “ **Disability Verification Information** ”). 

A competent authority qualified to attest to a User’s Disability Verification Information must confirm the Disability Verification Information. Users can provide this confirmation in different formats, which will include at least some of the following Personally Identifiable Information about the competent authority, which may be attributed to the User as part of their Disability Verification Information: 

  * name;
  * title/professional specialty;
  * licensing authority;
  * license number;
  * place of employment;
  * address;
  * telephone number; and/or
  * email address.

We collect Disability Verification Information in order to ensure that we are providing our Services in accordance with international copyright law, and particularly the disability accommodation treaty known as the Marrakesh Treaty as implemented in jurisdictions where we make our Services available. For more information about The Marrakesh Treaty and our obligations thereunder, please email us at [custserv@LearningAlly.org](mailto:custserv@learningally.org) or call us at 800-221-4792. 

#### (c) Providing Personally Identifiable Information on behalf of Another User:

Given the nature of our Services, a User may provide us with information on behalf of an individual who wishes to use our Services or act as a competent authority (see Section 1(b), “ **Disability Verification Information** ”). 

**If a User provides us with Personally Identifiable Information about another User in their capacity as a parent, a guardian, a school administrator, a public guardian, and/or a patient providing confirmation from a competent authority regarding Disability Verification Information, this must only be done after the providing User has obtained consent from the other User to the collection, storage and use of their Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with this Policy.**

#### (d) Use of Cookies:

Cookies may be used to enhance User experience when using our Services. Cookies are pieces of information that we transfer to a device’s storage through browser technologies to enable our systems to recognize that particular device and browser and to provide features such as remembering customized settings for using our Services and saving passwords. 

Most people consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard, and most browsers are set to accept cookies. However, Users can alter the configuration of their browser to refuse cookies. By doing so, however, it is possible that some areas of our website will not function optimally when viewed. 

We may use Google's remarketing technology to advertise to individuals who have previously visited our website when those visitors go to other websites participating in the Google Display Network. Learning Ally and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party and third-party cookies together to inform and optimize ads based on a visitor's past visits to our website. Users can find more information about remarketing or opting-out of the Google remarketing cookie here. 

#### (e) Internet Protocol Address:

We collect an internet protocol (“ **IP** ”) address from a User who accesses our Services. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to a device when it is connected to the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our website and smartphone app, analyze trends, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve our Services. IP addresses are not linked to Personally Identifiable Information. 

### Non-Personal Electronic Information:

We use non-personal electronic information, such as log files that record and collect information about general site traffic, site usage, and length of stay. We may use this data to improve our Services’ performance or content. This data is used in aggregate and does not contain Personally Identifiable Information. 

Learning Ally uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“ **Google** ”). Google Analytics collects information anonymously and reports trends without identifying individual visitors. Anyone can opt out of Google Analytics. For more information about how to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics, Users can visit [this Google page](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout&sa=D&ust=1572539075540000). 

## 2\. Storing Information

All information provided to us is transmitted using Secure Sockets Layer (“ **SSL** ”) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets a browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before it is sent to us. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our website that is only accessible by Learning Ally employees who need access to Personally Identifiable Information to perform a specific job. Voluntarily submitted data we collect through our website is stored on a secure, password protected server. Vendors we use to store data (see Section 3, “Sharing Information”) use industry-standard encryption technologies in the receipt and transfer of voluntarily submitted data. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect Users’ information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information. 

#### (f) Location of Information:

We store information, including Personally Identifiable Information, in the U.S. We will not store it in Canada or elsewhere. This means that Users’ information may be accessible to U.S. courts, law enforcement and national security authorities. 

## 3\. Sharing Information

We limit the use of Personally Identifiable Information and other information as follows: providing our Services, processing donations, informing Users about Learning Ally and its programs and improving our Services and content. We may send Users information about our Services, invitations to special events or solicitations for donations, in accordance with relevant anti-spam laws. 

We do not sell Personally Identifiable Information, nor do we use Personally Identifiable Information from education records to market to students. We may send Users periodic emails on a variety of topics. A User may start or stop receiving such emails at any time by sending an email to [custserv@LearningAlly.org](mailto:custserv@LearningAlly.org)., or by following unsubscribe or mail preferences links in those emails. 

There are circumstances where we may share information without notice or consent when required by law or lawful authority. For example, from time to time, we may be compelled by legal action to release information (e.g., statutory reporting obligation, search warrant, court order, bankruptcy or insolvency proceedings etc.). 

We may also share information with consultants and affiliates for internal business purposes or to properly offer the Services, such as with our internet hosting provider, payment processor or other third parties, such as set out in Section 3(a). 

#### (g) Third Party Service Providers:

There are certain services supplied to us by third parties, such as email platform hosts, server hosts or payment processors. These third parties are authorized to use a User’s Personally Identifiable Information only as necessary to provide these services to us, and in a manner consistent with this Policy. We have selected third party service providers who will only use User information in compliance with this Policy, but they may have their own specific policies regarding the collection, storage and use of Personally Identifiable Information. Please note that third parties may store a User’s Personally Identifiable Information anywhere in the world, and it may be accessible to foreign courts, law enforcement and national security authorities in the jurisdiction(s) where it is transferred or stored. 

#### (h) Like-Minded Organizations:

At times, in order to expand our list of prospective donors or schools, we may purchase lists of like-minded organizations from a trustworthy third party. To maintain our costs, we on occasion will exchange our mailing list with other like-minded organizations, through the same reputable third party. Email addresses are never sold. Users can update their preferences by emailing [custserv@LearningAlly.org](mailto:custserv@learningally.org). 

## Other Websites

Our Services may contain links or otherwise rely on other sites, services, platforms or apps (“ **Other Services** ”), which have information and services that may be helpful. These Other Services may have their own privacy policies and practices. When a User transacts with these Other Services by clicking on a link or starting a process involving those Other Services, we cannot control what happens with their Personally Identifiable Information. We assume no responsibility for the privacy policies or information collection practices of Other Services. Users should read the privacy policies on all such Other Services as their policies may be different than ours. 

## 4\. Access to Information; Retention

#### (a) Review and Correction:

A User may, upon request, review and correct the Personally Identifiable Information that we have collected from them or from another User on their behalf (see Section 1(c), “Providing Personally Identifiable Information on behalf of Another User”). Such procedures may not, however, compromise the security, integrity and privacy of our proprietary databases or databases licensed from third party companies. 

#### (b) Retention:

We will retain a User’s Personally Identifiable Information for only so long as reasonably required for us to properly provide the Services to that User and to ensure and enforce the terms of our agreement(s) with them. 

## 5\. Changes to Policy

This Policy, as well as policies specific to the various operating departments within Learning Ally, will be periodically assessed against new technologies, business practices and our members’ changing needs. We may, from time to time, modify this Policy to reflect legal, technological and other developments. 

We reserve the right at any time and without notice to change this Policy by posting such changes through our Services. Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting. 

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or our Services, please contact our Privacy Officer at the following address: 

Learning Ally, Inc.  
20 Roszel Rd  
Princeton, NJ 08540 

Attention: Privacy Officer 

We can also be reached via e-mail at [custserv@LearningAlly.org](mailto:custserv@learningally.org)., and if your subject line includes Attention: Privacy Officer, we will route it accordingly.
